



# **Pratik Panda**

**Product Designer** 

## **About**

Hello! My name is Pratik Panda. A large section of my work focuses on Visual Design, Product Illustration, and Interaction. Having worked as a designer for 3 years my experience includes dealing with teams of multiple domains.

Βē



in

### Contact

+91 933 742 1359

www.ipratik.design ☑

ipratik.design@gmail.com

3031, Bhubaneswar- 751002, India

## Language

English
Hindi
Odia

#### Skills

Sketch Figma

Adobe XD
Protopie

Invision

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Dimension

 $\mathsf{HTML}$ 

CSS

UX/UI Design
Websites Design
Mobile App Design

Prototyping & Testing Iconography Typography

#### Education

2017-2021

 College of Engineering and Technology Pursuing a Bachelor's degree in Textile Sciences and Engineering, which emphasises on fabric manufacturing and associated technology

2016-2017

Orissa Engineering College Dropped out of the college in the freshman year but acquired knowledge on the basics of a few programming languages during my short tenure

2004-2016

Pracheen Kala Kendra Academy Completed by Bachelor's degree in Fine and Studio Arts and gained a huge amount of knowledge on the specific domain and took it as a profession as well

2004-2016

St. Xavier's High School Completed by secondary and intermediary education from St. Xavier's High School affiliated to Central Board of Secondary Education

## **Experience**

2020-Present

Nirmitee.io

Worked on numerous projects involving product designing. The whole process offered meaningful insights at different levels of production, from scratch to delivery

2020-2021

Milk Mantra

Engaged as a product designer for enhancing the online delivery system. Moreover contributed towards developing a LMS platform for a new product launching soon

2020-2021

**Gamiac Studios** 

A new customer support system where a complete CRM platform has been developed along with MVP testing by the end of 2020

2020-2021

Genetico

A part of the developers' team building platforms for detection of rare diseases through some contemporary genetic studies and research

2020-202

Bizman

Worked on a broad range of projects managing websites, mobile applications, branding projects and creative

aspects of marketing

These organisations ranging from budding startups to established companies, gave me the opportunity to develop products with my crewmates some of which have been shipped successfully rest being under the development process. Some projects are not meant to be shared according to the company rules. I have gathered expertise in preparing a roadmap to be followed during product development which can ensure smooth and organised workflow. I emphasise on data collection through user research for mapping and building the whole architecture including insertion of wireframes, designing and prototyping high-fidelity screens. Apart from that I maintain parallel coordination with the development team to abide to the deadline for product shipment